<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects | Wenbin Zhai&#39;s homepage</title>
    <link>https://wenbinzhai.github.io/project/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://wenbinzhai.github.io/project/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Projects</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://wenbinzhai.github.io/media/icon_hudd52f536e0ed7a09c04185e95455d949_168999_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Projects</title>
      <link>https://wenbinzhai.github.io/project/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>FedS3A</title>
      <link>https://wenbinzhai.github.io/project/feds3a/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://wenbinzhai.github.io/project/feds3a/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Working on the design of &lt;strong&gt;Federated Semi-Supervised and Semi-Asynchronous Learning (FedS&lt;sup&gt;3&lt;/sup&gt;A)&lt;/strong&gt; for anomaly detection in IoT networks, addressing a more realistic semi-supervised scenario. The framework introduces a &lt;strong&gt;semi-asynchronous model update and staleness-tolerant distribution scheme&lt;/strong&gt; to balance round efficiency and detection performance. It accounts for &lt;strong&gt;the staleness of local models and the participation frequency of clients&lt;/strong&gt; to ensure fair contributions to the global model. Additionally, a &lt;strong&gt;group-based aggregation function&lt;/strong&gt; is employed to handle non-IID data, while difference transmission using sparse matrices is adopted to reduce communication overhead. (2022–present, submitted to the &lt;strong&gt;IEEE Internet of Things Journal (IOTJ) [CCF C, SCI-Q1])&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ETD</title>
      <link>https://wenbinzhai.github.io/project/etd/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://wenbinzhai.github.io/project/etd/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Proposed an &lt;strong&gt;Efficient Time Delay Attack Detection Scheme (ETD)&lt;/strong&gt; for UAV networks, addressing a relatively underexplored attack surface. The scheme begins with a comprehensive selection of delay-related features across four dimensions: &lt;strong&gt;delay, node, message, and connection&lt;/strong&gt;. Using one-class classification, a model is trained based on these features to evaluate the forwarding behaviors of all nodes and compute their trust values. Malicious nodes are then distinguished from benign ones based on these trust values. (2022, published in the &lt;strong&gt;IEEE Transactions on Information Forensics and Security (TIFS) [CORE A, CCF A, SCI-Q1]&lt;/strong&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HOTD</title>
      <link>https://wenbinzhai.github.io/project/hotd/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://wenbinzhai.github.io/project/hotd/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Proposed a &lt;strong&gt;Holistic Cross-Layer Time Delay Attack Detection Framework (HOTD)&lt;/strong&gt; for UAV networks, designed to effectively identify time delay attacks that are both challenging to detect and straightforward to implement. The framework begins with a comprehensive selection of delay-related features across each layer of UAV networks. Using supervised learning, a &lt;strong&gt;consistency model&lt;/strong&gt; is constructed to map the relationship between these features and their corresponding forwarding delays. Based on this model, the &lt;strong&gt;consistency degree&lt;/strong&gt; of each node is calculated. Finally, the K-Means clustering algorithm is employed to classify nodes as either malicious or benign based on their consistency degrees. (2021–2022, published in the &lt;strong&gt;Journal of Parallel and Distributed Computing (JPDC) [CORE A, CCF B, SCI-Q1]&lt;/strong&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PAR</title>
      <link>https://wenbinzhai.github.io/project/par/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://wenbinzhai.github.io/project/par/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Proposed a &lt;strong&gt;Power-Aware Routing (PAR)&lt;/strong&gt; Algorithm to optimize energy consumption in delay-constrained UAV networks. The algorithm incorporates the &lt;strong&gt;adjustable power&lt;/strong&gt; levels of UAVs and leverages pre-planned trajectory information to calculate encounters at different power levels. Using this data, a &lt;strong&gt;power-aware encounter tree&lt;/strong&gt; is constructed to identify the transmission path with minimal energy consumption from the source to the destination, while adhering to delay constraints. (2020–2021, published in &lt;strong&gt;WASA 2022 [CCF C]&lt;/strong&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
